Hello and welcome
您好 欢迎您使用多功能卢静学习
to Multiparadigm Data Science
with the Wolfram Language,
欢迎使用Wolfram语言学习多路径数据科学
Section 4: Assembling
a Multiparadigm Toolset.
第4节：组装多路径工具集
The very first section
of this course,
本课程的第一部分
Building a Project Workflow,
构建项目工作流
provided an overview
提供了概述
of the multiparadigm
project workflow.
关于多路径项目工作流
Sections 2 and 3 provided
more details
第2节和第3节提供了更多细节
on functionality useful
for the wrangle
在功能性和有用方面
and explore stages
of the workflow.
在工作流的wrangle和explore阶段
In section 4, we'll continue
with the multiparadigm approach,
在第4节中，我们将继续使用多路径方法
and look at different algorithms
and techniques
并研究对分析工作流阶段
useful for the analyze stage
of the workflow.
有用的算法和技术
The goal is to assemble
a multiparadigm toolset
我们的目标是组装一个多路径工具集
that can be incorporated
into the workflow
该工具集可以合并到工作流中
and used to drive it
with questions.
并用问题驱动它
Instead of restricting ourselves
to traditional techniques
与其局限于传统的
associated with specific
kinds of data,
特定类型的数据技术
let's reach out across disciplines
不如让我们跨学科
to use the tool that is most
suited to answer our questions.
使用最适合回答我们问题的工具
But before we begin,
但在开始之前
let's quickly review
some of the terminology
让我们简单回顾一些术语
commonly used in data science.
这些术语常用于数据科学中
These have been borrowed
他们都是从统计学和
from both statistics
and machine learning.
机器学习中借鉴的
For a data sample x,
对于一个数据样本x
x1, x2 and so on are known
as the features of the sample
x1、x2等被称为样本的特征
or predictor variables
or independent variables.
或预测变量或自变量
y is the dependent variable
or the response variable
y是因变量 或响应变量
or output value or label.
或输出值 或标签
The model itself
can either be a function
模型本身可以是一个函数
with associated assumptions
and optimization criteria
其相关的假设和优化准则
used to approximate the behavior
suggested by the data,
用于取数据所建议的近似的行为
or it can refer to a blackbox
represented by an algorithm
模型也可以引用由算法表示的黑盒
that takes training data as input
该算法将训练数据作为输入
and produces predictions of labels
and values as output.
生成的预测标签或值作为输出
Parameters are the values
in the model that are not assumed
参数是模型中未假定的值
by the predictor
or response variables.
这些值由预测变量或响应变量假定
A big part of machine learning
机器学习的很大一部分
often involves learning
these parameter values.
通常涉及学习这些参数值
Training is the process
of identifying the function
训练是识别函数
or the algorithm
and the corresponding parameters
或算法以及相应的参数的过程
that best represent
the relationship between the input
参数最能代表输入
and the output.
和输出之间的关系
Let's look at a few questions
让我们看看几个问题
that data science projects
often try to answer
这些问题通常是数据科学项目
with the help of data.
试图借助数据来回答的
To begin with,
首先
we have of the most frequently
asked questions
我们最常问的问题
that is of the type
is this A or B,
类型是A或B
or even A or B or C or D or E?
甚至是A或B或C或D或E？
In data science,
this is known as classification—
在数据科学中 这被称为分类—
trying to figure out if a sample
belongs to class 1 or class 2,
试图找出一个样本属于1类还是2类
so questions along the lines of:
因此问题大致如下
Given an image, can we label it
as a cat or a dog?
给定一个图像 我们能给它贴上猫还是狗的标签？
Given text of an email,
can we say if it's spam or not?
给定一封邮件的文本 我们能判断它是否是垃圾邮件吗？
For text in different languages,
can we label each piece
对于不同语言的文本 我们能给每一篇文章贴上
as English or French
or Arabic or something else?
英文、法文、阿拉伯文或其他的标签吗？
Can we classify a Facebook post
according to its topic—
我们能根据Facebook的主题
say, technology, food, travel?
比如科技、食物、旅游来分类吗？
Supervised machine learning
is a technique
监督式机器学习是一种技术
where the algorithm
attempts to learn
其中算法尝试去学习
from training examples
of input-output pairs
从输入输出对训练示例中
to predict output labels
or values for new input.
以预测新输入后的输出标签或值
Classification perhaps accounts
for the widest application
分类也许能解释为什么
of supervised machine learning
to real-world problems.
在现实生活问题中有监督机器学习应用最广泛
It is the algorithm of choice
这是算法的选择
if your problem can be posed
as the question,
如果你的问题是
"is this A or B or C
or D or E," and so on.
A或B或C或D或E等问题
So it is a descriptive
modeling task
因此 这是一个描述性建模任务
which tries to predict
the class label of a sample
它试图预测样本的类标签
based on the previously
labeled instances.
根据先前标记的实例
Here's some training data where
each sample has two features,
以下是一些培训数据 每个样本都有两个特征
age and income,
年龄和收入
and a predefined class label,
high or low,
以及一个预先定义的类别标签（高或低）
representing the credit risk
代表假设由个体
posed by
the hypothetical individual.
所构成的信用风险
This is the target label we'd
like to predict for new samples.
这是我们想预测新样品的目标标签
Using this data,
we'd like to infer a function
使用这些数据 我们想推断出一个函数
to map from the feature values
to a label.
从特征值映射到标签
And once we have the function,
we can use it to predict a label
一旦我们有了这个函数 我们就可以用它来预测标签
when given the feature values
of a new data point.
当给定一个新的新数据点的特征值时
Classify is
the machine learning superfunction
分类是一项机器学习超功能
available in the Wolfram Language.
在Wolfram语言中可用的
It's perfect for the multiparadigm
project workflow
它非常适合多路径项目工作流
as it automates
the process of classification.
因为它自动化了分类过程
It picks the optimum algorithm
internally
它在内部选择最佳算法
according to the available data,
根据可用的数据
whether it's numeric
or text or sound or images
不管是数字、文本、声音或图像
or any combinations of these.
或它们的任何组合
The labeled training examples
带样本的训练示例
are used to learn
a ClassifierFunction
被用于学习ClassifierFunction(分类器函数)
that can be used
to classify and label new samples.
然后可用于对新样本进行分类和标记
It can also be used
to find the probability
它还可以用来找出样本
that the sample belongs
to a certain class.
属于某一类的概率
Here we see how the probability
of the sample belonging to class A
在这里，我们看到样本属于A类的概率
changes as the value
of the numeric feature changes.
是随着数值特征值的变化而变化
Let's revisit
the famous Fisher's iris dataset
让我们重温一下著名Fisher's Iris数据集
that we worked with in
the Get to Know Your Data section.
我们在"了解您的数据"部分使用过
This famous dataset
has the recorded
该数据集记录了
sepal length, sepal width,
萼片长度、萼片宽度
petal length and petal width
of the samples
花瓣长度和花瓣宽度
from three different species
of the iris flower.
四种从三种不同品种鸢尾花中得到的特征
Given these four features,
the classification task
鉴于这四个特征 分类任务是
is to predict the species
of a new sample.
预测新样本的物种
Here's some training data
for us to train the classifier
这里有一些训练数据 我们可以训练分类器
and some test data to see how well
the classifier is performing.
还有一些测试数据可以看看分类器的性能如何
A quick visual exploration
of the features
通过对特征的快速视觉探索
shows us
that they are well-suited
我们发现这些特征非常适合于
for discriminating
between the three classes
区分三类物种
of species,
and can be directly used
to build the classifier
并且可以直接用于构建分类器
without any feature engineering.
而无需任何特征工程
We feed the training data
into Classify.
我们将训练数据输入分类
Here are the predicted
class labels
下面是一些预测类样本
for 10 random samples
from the test data.
从测试数据中随机抽取的10个样本
We can find more details about
the classifier that was created.
我们可以找到与创建的分类器相关的更多详细信息
Along with the algorithm
that was used, decision tree,
随着所使用的算法，决策树
we can find out the values
of the various parameters
我们可以找出用于该算法的
used for this algorithm.
各种参数的值
We can see
how the training progressed
我们可以看到培训的进展情况
and what was
the performance on the test set.
以及在测试集上的表现
Accuracy shows how many samples
准确度显示有多少样本
had their class labels
predicted correctly.
他们的类标签预测正确
It's not enough
to just build a classifier.
仅仅建立一个分类器是不够的
We need to evaluate
its performance
我们需要评估它的性能
to see if it's providing
reasonable output.
看看它是否提供了合理的输出
This is where
the test data is useful.
这就是测试数据有用的地方
Since we know the labels
of these samples,
既然我们知道这些样本的标签
we can match them
against the predicted labels
所以我们可以将它们与预测的标签进行匹配
to see how well
the classifier is doing.
看看分类器的表现如何
Accuracy is one useful measure
of performance,
准确度是衡量性能的一个有用的指标
giving the fraction
of correctly classified examples.
通过给出正确分类示例的分数
The confusion matrix
is another useful measure,
混淆矩阵是另一个有用的度量
which shows at a glance
how many samples of each class
它可以一眼看出每个类中有多少个样本
were labeled correctly
as belonging to that class
被正确地标记为属于该类
or mislabeled
as belonging to another class.
或者错误地标记为属于另一个类
ClassifierMeasurements
can be used to compute
ClassifierMeasurements可以用来计算
a whole range of metrics
一系列度量
useful for evaluating
the performance of a classifier.
这些度量用于评估分类器性能
We can find examples
from one class
我们可以找到示例
that were mislabeled
as another class.
它从一个类中被错误标记为另一类
Here are the probabilities
from the classifier function,
下面是来自分类器函数的概率
which shows why
the mistakes were made.
它显示了为什么会出错
The iris dataset contained
only numeric features.
虹膜数据集只包含数字特征
Here is an example
where we build a classifier
下面是一个例子 我们构建分类器
using labeled images of trees
as input
用树的标记图像作为输入
to predict the species
of the tree as output.
以预测树的种类作为输出
We see the logistic regression
algorithm was chosen,
我们看到逻辑回归算法被选中
and it achieved an accuracy of 89%.
它达到了89%的准确率
All the maples in the test data
were classified correctly,
所有的枫树在测试数据中分类正确
but there were misclassifications
for eucalyptus, oak and pine.
但桉树、橡树和松树存在分类错误
These were
the best-classified samples
这些是最佳分类样本
with 100% certainty,
100%确定的
and these were
the worst-classified samples.
而这些样本是最差的分类样本
These are the samples
这些是被错误分类的样本
of eucalyptuses
misclassified as oaks.
桉树被错误分为橡树
Here's yet another example
of building a classifier
这是另一个构建分类器的例子
using text input.
通过文本输入
We import the text
from works of famous authors
我们将著名作家作品导入文本
like Shakespeare, Jane Austen
and Agatha Christie.
例如莎士比亚、简奥斯丁、阿加莎克里斯蒂
Now let's try to train a classifier
on these texts
现在让我们试着在文本上训练一个分类器
to predict the author when given
a sample of his or her writing.
以便在给定写作样本时预测作者
A simple Markov model
is able to do a good job
一个简单的马尔可夫模型可以很好的完成这项任务
of predicting the author
from a sample of their writing.
从他们的写作样本中预测作者
Classify can be configured to use
分类可以配置为
one of the many well-known
classification algorithms
各种著名的分类算法之一
as a method,
作为一种方法
whether it's logistic regression,
nearest neighbors, Naive Bayes,
无论是逻辑回归、最近邻，朴素贝叶斯
decision trees,
gradient-boosted trees,
决策树、梯度增强树
random forests, Markov models,
support vector machines
随机森林、马尔可夫模型、支持向量
or even neural networks.
或者甚至是神经网络
Let's compare the performance
of two different classifiers
让我们比较两个不同的分类器
trained on the same data.
在同一数据上训练的不同性能
One is set to use
logistic regression
其中一个设置为使用逻辑回归
and the other Naive Bayes.
另一个使用朴素贝叶斯
We see that
the decision probability
我们发现 对于属于a 类的样本
for a sample belonging to class A
reduces gradually
逻辑回归分类器的决策概率逐渐降低
for the logistic regression
classifier,
对于朴素贝叶斯
whereas it is a sharp change
for the Naive Bayes classifier.
则是一个急剧的变化
Classify can also be customized
分类也可以通过
by setting a specific value
as the indeterminate threshold
设置一个特定的值作为不确定的阈值来制定
so that the classifier
attempts to make
因此分类器只有在样本
a confident prediction
属于一个类的概率足够高时
only when the probability
of the sample belonging to a class
才会尝试进行置信预测
is high enough.
Since we set
the IndeterminateThreshold
因为在本例中
to a high value of 0.9
in this example,
我们将不确定状态的阈值设置为0.9
the classifier does not
make a decision
所以分类器不会做出决定
and instead just returns the label
as indeterminate.
而是将标签返回为不确定
This can be useful
in fine-tuning the performance
这对于微调分类器的性能
of a classifier
to avoid false positives.
以避免误报非常有用
Classify can also be customized
to assign a specific utility value
Classify还可以为每个可能的实际和预测标签
to each possible pairing
of actual and predicted labels.
定制为一个特定的实际程序值
For example,
in this mushroom dataset,
例如，在这个蘑菇数据集中
the classifier tries to predict
分类器试图预测蘑菇
whether the mushroom
is edible or not.
是否可以食用
Each record is a mushroom sample
每一个记录都是蘑菇样品
along with its label,
edible or poisonous.
和它的标签 食用或者有毒
Once we have trained a classifier,
we can compare
一旦我们训练了一个分类器 我们可以
the predicted
versus actual class labels
将预测的和实际的分类标签进行比较
to see how many
poisonous mushrooms
看看有多少有毒蘑菇
got predicted as edible.
可被预测为可食的
In this scenario, we'd really
like to avoid false positives,
在这种情况下，我们真的希望避免假阳性
that is, poisonous mushrooms
getting labeled as edible.
也就是说，有毒蘑菇被贴上食用标签
We can set the utility function
to penalize such predictions
我们可以设置效用函数来惩罚这种预测
more than the false negatives,
而不是假阴性
that is, edible mushrooms
being classified as poisonous.
即食用菌被归类为有毒的
We'd also like the classifier
to declare labels as indeterminate
我们还希望分类器为不清楚的决策声明
for decisions that are not clear,
标签为不确定的
so we set up a utility function,
as seen here.
因此我们设置了一个效用函数 如下图所示
The new classifier
trained with the utility function
用效用函数训练的新分类器
predicts many more samples
as indeterminate,
可以预测更多的样本为不确定样本
but also has
fewer false positives.
但也有较少的误报
Lastly we can tune
the performance of the classifier
最后，我们可以通过设置性能目标
by setting a performance goal.
来调整分类器的性能
A classifier's performance
can be optimized
分类器的性能可以根据
for training speed,
actual runtime speed,
训练速度、实际运行速度
memory usage
or accuracy of predictions.
内存使用率或预测精度进行优化
Here is a comparison
of the training times
这里比较了两个
of two classifiers
with different performance goals.
不同性能目标的分类器的训练次数
Naturally the training time
of the classifier
当然 为了准确度
whose performance
is being optimized for accuracy
而优化性能的分类器的训练时间
takes longer to train.
需要更长的时间来训练
In summary,
we looked at classification
总之 我们把分类看作是一个有监督的机器学习任务
as a supervised
machine learning task
是一个有监督的机器学习任务
for predicting labels
for new samples,
在一组先前标记的训练样本的帮助下
with the help of a set
训练样本的帮助下
of previously labeled
training samples.
预测新样本的标签
We applied the machine learning
superfunction Classify
我们将机器学习超函数应用于具有
on various datasets
with numerical features,
数值特征、图像、文本
images, text or even combinations
of different types.
甚至不同类型组合的各种数据集的分类
We used ClassifierMeasurements
我们使用分类器度量
to evaluate the performance
of the classifiers,
来评估分类器的性能
and we looked at different options
available for customizing Classify
我们查看了定制分类的不同选项
to suit the need
for the task at hand—
以满足手头任务需要
among them Method to use a
specific classification algorithm,
其中包括使用特定分类算法的方法
UtilityFunction
and IndeterminateThreshold
效用函数和不确定性状态的阈值
to control predictions
来控制预测
and PerformanceGoal
to optimize performance
和优化性能
according to different criteria.
根据不同的准则